

RAJA NARAPAREDDY

n.rtheja@outlook.com / C: 682-583-5389 Manchester, CT 06040

PORTFOLIOS

- https://rnarapareddy-tathekalva.github.io/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajasekhartheja/

SUMMARY

Knowledgeable and 7+ years experienced Senior Software Engineer well-versed in OOP concepts and design patterns. Excellent API design, implementation and integration abilities paired with significant project leadership background. Exceptional success in delivering complex software development projects on time and within budget to exceed expectations.

SKILLS

- **J2EE Tech Stack**: Spring MVC, Spring Boot 2.x, Grails 2.x, Hibernate, Mybatis, REST, SOAP
- Spring Cloud: Eureka, Cloud Config, Cloud Stream, Zuul, Hystrix
- Platform and Containerization: OpenShift, Kubernetes, Docker
- Servers: Apache Tomcat, Wildfly, WebSphere Application Server
- UI: AngularJS, ExtJS, GSP, JS

- Message Brokers: RabbitMQ, Kafka
- Tools: Pentaho ETL, Birt Report, Oracle APEX
- Agile development methodologies
- Solution Development Life Cycle Tools: Jira, Confluence, Bamboo, Bitbucket, Jenkins

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer / University of Connecticut - Storrs, CT

01/2020 - Current

- Architected an Entity Driven based Spring Boot Microservice integration project.
- The Integration project was designed for the data flow across the Unifier, Kuali Financial System (KFS), Jaggaer systems.
- Used Red Hat Openshift 'Platform as a service (PaaS)' extensively for building and deploying the spring cloud applications.
- RabbitMQ is used as the message broker in the developed microservice architecture.
- Tightly integrated Spring cloud with openshift, leading to maximize the usage the PaaS components like configmap, secret and service registry.
- Developed webproject for the University Parking Services Payroll Deductions based on Oracle Apex.

Lead Java Developer / Washington University In St. Louis - St Louis, MO

02/2018 - 01/2020

Biospecimen Management System: The application that has been designed to support support bio-specimen tracking, inventory management, and reporting for clinical trials.

- Extensive hands-on experience in computational analysis of clinical data in observational studies.
- Involve in all phases of the software Development Life Cycle including requirements gathering, design and

- implementation application, testing and maintenance support.
- Lead developer on numerous projects utilizing Java EE, Grails, Spring, Struts frameworks to create fully integrated Bio-specimen Management Systems.
- Proficient in working with Pentaho Reporting engine which includes design of various ETL tools and developing the reports using Birt report engine.
- Expertise in production support activities.

Senior Application Developer / Infosys/CVS - Woonsocket, RI

08/2016 - 02/2018

Enterprise Patient Hub: A Master Data Management application for handling patient data from sources systems.

- Experience in handling PHI data, and maintain high-availability application.
- Hands on experience on WebSphere Application Server (WAS)
- Sound knowledge in working with WAS setup environment, configuring MQ's, JNDIS, Data sources and other J2EE applications related configurations.
- Extensive use of MEM JAVA API's (Infosphere MDM) in interacting with MDM Server.
- Experience in IBM Workbench to configure Infosphere MDM
- Designed and developed the MDM Java handlers for implementing Pre/Post Mem transactions.
- In-depth knowledge in debugging production related issues as a part of Production Support team. Led the offshore team on daily basis.
- Production support for the application and handling of critical issues in imely manner.

IT Analyst / TATA Consultancy Services - Chennai, India

08/2011 - 08/2014

- Performance tuning of the application and using Spring batch for the bulk processing of inserts and messages.
- Experience in using IDEs Eclipse, intellij, WebShpere for Application development
- Sound knowledge in performance tuning of SQL queries, JAVA applications.
- Worked on Spring MVC, REST Web-services.
- Worked on Oracle & SQL Server as the backend databases and integrated with Hibernate to retrieve Data Access Objects.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas At Arlington - Arlington, TX **Master of Science**

08/2016

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

 Honored for solely developing the cost cutting migration project used for data migration of a Bio-Specimen inventory software. This development helped the company to apt for opensource version of the product and avoiding the huge licensing cost of the commercial version of the same.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer
- Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Administration